A Register of the Mark V. Vishniak Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Mark V. Vishniak Papers
circa 1910-1995
70000
Hoover Institution Archives
19 manuscript boxes (7.9 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches, writings, and clippings, relating to Russian and Soviet history, Russian revolutionists, Russian émigrés, and political conditions in the Soviet Union by the Russian historian and Socialist Revolutionary Party leader.
Vishniak, M. V. (Mark Ven'iaminovich), b. 1883.
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1970
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (24 reels).
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biography / Administrative History
The Russian author and pre-Bolshevik politician was born in Moscow on January 15, 1883 later graduating from Moscow University. As a law professor at the Moscow Pedagogical Institute, he was an ardent Socialist Revolutionary, who, in 1918, was secretary of the only freely elected Constituent Assembly in his country's history. He held the post only seventeen hours, until Lenin disbanded the Parliament. After fleeing to Paris and then to New York in 1940 Vishniak later became Time magazine's senior specialist on Soviet affairs and wrote 22 books. He died in New York City in 1976.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches, writings, and clippings, relating to Russian and Soviet history, Russian revolutionists, Russian émigrés, and political conditions in the Soviet Union by the Russian historian and Socialist Revolutionary Party leader.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series: Correspondence, Biographical File, Speeches and Writings, Subject File, Photographs and Miscellany.
Partiia sotsialistov-revoliutsionerov.; Revolutionaries--Russia.; Russians in foreign countries.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.
- Correspondence, 1917-1968 and undated. (Box 1)
  General note
  See also Subject File.
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes related materials such as articles, clippings, memoranda, notes, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Alternate spellings of names in parenthesis
  - Unidentified
    - undated (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1926-1967 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Abel, Sherry, 1957 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Abramovich, Rafail, 1943-1956 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Achair, Alexey, 1939 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Acklom, George, 1942 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Adamovich, George, 1939-1968 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Aktsyn, V., 1943 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Aldanov (Landay), Mark, 1932-1956
    - 1932-1940 (Folder 1: 9)
    - 1941-1943 (Folder 1: 10)
    - 1944 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 1945 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1946-1956 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Aleksandrova, Vera, 1962 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Alekseev, Nikolai, 1951 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Alexandrovich, M., 1940 (Folder 1: 16)
  - Alexinsky, G, 1963 (Folder 1: 17)
  - Aley, Maxwell, 1941 (Folder 1: 18)
  - Allen, Carolyn E., 1943 (Folder 1: 19)
  - Allen, Stuart, 1940 (Folder 1: 20)
  - Altshuller, Ksenia, 1966, 1969 (Folder 1: 21)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1946 (Folder 1: 22)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1944 (Folder 1: 23)
  - Andreev, Vadim, 1938-1939 (Folder 1: 24)
  - Angof, Chatles, 1948 (Folder 1: 25)
  - Anin, David, S., 1965-1969 (Folder 1: 26)
  - Annenkov, IUrii, 1939-1940 (Folder 1: 27)
  - Archbishop of San Francisco and Western United States, 1948-1968 (Folder 1: 28)
  - Arendt, Hannah, 1947 (Folder 1: 29)
  - Arkin, Leon, 1941 (Folder 1: 30)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton F., 1946-1955 (Folder 1: 31)
  - Armstrong, Suzanne, 1947-1948 (Folder 1: 32)
  - Aroson, Gregor, 1938-1945 (Folder 1: 33)
  - Arutiunov, Nark, undated (Folder 1: 34)
  - Asher, Harvey, 1965 (Folder 1: 35)
  - Averbakh, Lavrentii, 1944 (Folder 1: 36)
  - Avrami, Z., 1960 (Folder 1: 37)
  - Avverino, N., 1949-1950 (Folder 1: 38)
  - Avxentieff, N., 1940 (Folder 1: 39)
  - Axelbank, Herman, 1968 (Folder 1: 40)
  - Babkin, Boris P., 1948-1949 (Folder 1: 41)
  - Baratz, Leon, 1953 (Folder 1: 42)
  - Barners, Ksenia, 1945 (Folder 1: 43)
  - Baron, Salo W., 1943 (Folder 1: 44)
  - Barrett, Laura, 1943-1946 (Folder 1: 45)
  - Bart, S., 1939 (Folder 1: 46)
  - Baskin Josef, 1944-1945 (Folder 1: 47)
  - Baum, Nora, 1951 (Folder 1: 48)
  - Baylenn, Ken, 1967 (Folder 1: 49)
  - Beklemishev, A., 1959 (Folder 1: 50)
  - Beliaeva, V., 1950 (Folder 1: 51)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1947 (Folder 1: 52)
  - Belotsvetov, Nikolai, 1933 (Folder 1: 53)
  - Belsky, Abe, 1943 (Folder 1: 54)
  - Benua, Alexander, 1938 (Folder 1: 55)
  - Berberova, Nina, 1945-1965 (Folder 1: 56)
  - Beresney, T., 1943 (Folder 1: 57)
  - Berg, A., 1955 (Folder 1: 58)
  - Bergel'son, A., 1944 (Folder 1: 59)
  - Berlin, Pavel A., 1938-1945 (Folder 1: 60)
  - Bernard, William S., 1945 (Folder 1: 61)
  - Bernstein, Ossip, 1945, 1957 (Folder 1: 62)
  - Binshtok, G., 1944 (Folder 1: 63)
  - Biondi, Arthur, 1949 (Folder 1: 64)
  - Bisk, Alexander, 1963 (Folder 1: 65)
  - Bitsilli, Petr M., 1938 (Folder 1: 66)
  - Blagova, M., 1955 (Folder 1: 67)
  - Blum, Leon, 1918-1946
    - undated (Folder 1: 68)
    - 1918-1932 (Folder 1: 69)
    - 1933 (Folder 1: 70)
    - 1934 (Folder 1: 71)
    - 1937-1946 (Folder 1: 72)
  - Bondarenko (Bond), Vladimir I., 1946-1969 (Box 2)
    - undated (Folder 2: 1)
    - 1946-1948 (Folder 2: 2)
    - 1950 (Folder 2: 3)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 2: 4)
    - 1953-1959 (Folder 2: 5)
    - 1962-1969 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Borisoff, N., 1942 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Borissoff, Aristarkh D., 1944 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Bourguina, Anna, 1966-1969 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Bourtzeff, Vadim L., 1938 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Brace, Richard, undated (Folder 2: 11)
  - Brams, IAkov, 1938 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Bramson, L., 1939 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Bramson, Sarah, 1938 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Bransovan, Constantine, 1969 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Braslansky, M., 1940 (Folder 2: 16)
  - Braunshvets, A., 1952 (Folder 2: 17)
  - Brianchaninov, Georgii, 1949 (Folder 2: 18)
  - Brockway, W.E., 1945 (Folder 2: 19)
  - Bromberg, IA., 1941 (Folder 2: 20)
  - Browder, Robert P., 1966 (Folder 2: 21)
  - Brutzkus, Julius, 1943 (Folder 2: 22)
  - Bulgakov, Valentin, 1939 (Folder 2: 23)
  - Bunin, Ivan, 1938-1939 (Folder 2: 24)
  - Butenko, V., 1952 (Folder 2: 25)
  - Campanari, E., 1940-1941 (Folder 2: 26)
  - Campbell, David P., 1967 (Folder 2: 27)
  - Caraher, Gerald J., 1965 (Folder 2: 28)
  - Carmichael, Joel, 1955 (Folder 2: 29)
  - Caruthers, F.D., 1946 (Folder 2: 30)
  - Casper, Sharon, 1976 (Folder 2: 31)
  - Chanels, Ellen, 1969 (Folder 2: 32)
  - Chanin, 1840 (Folder 2: 33)
  - Charasch, A.A., 1940 (Folder 2: 34)
  - Charnley, Mitchell V., 1967 (Folder 2: 35)
  - Chekhov Publishing House, 1952-1953 (Folder 2: 36)
  - Chernnoff, A.I., 1946, 1961 (Folder 2: 37)
  - Chestov, Lev I., 1937-1939 (Folder 2: 38)
  - Chilton, W.L., 1944 (Folder 2: 39)
  - Chyz, Yaroslav J., 1946 (Folder 2: 40)
  - Cohen, Abraham, 1947 (Folder 2: 41)
  - Cohen, Morris R., 1940 (Folder 2: 42)
  - Columbia University, 1942 (Folder 2: 43)
  - Connolly, Stephen, 1965-1967 (Folder 2: 44)
  - Cornwall, Barbara, 1960 (Folder 2: 45)
  - Counts, W.B., 1945-1946 (Folder 2: 46)
  - Crane, Robert T., 1941 (Folder 2: 47)
  - Credit Lyonnais, 1940 (Folder 2: 48)
  - Cross, Michel, 1941 (Folder 2: 49)
  - Cuningham, Charles E., 1945 (Folder 2: 50)
  - Cushman, Robert E., 1943 (Folder 2: 51)
  - Czapski, Joseph, 1946 (Folder 2: 52)
  - D'Ambra, Nina, 1943 (Folder 2: 53)
  - Dallin, Alexander, 1948 (Folder 2: 54)
  - Dallin David, J., 1942-1953 (Folder 2: 55)
  - Daly, Joan, C., 1967 (Folder 2: 56)
  - Damansky, A., 1939 (Folder 2: 57)
  - Dan, Lydia, 1958-1960 (Folder 2: 58)
  - Dashevsky, Louis, 1955 (Folder 2: 59)
  - Davar, 1940-1941 (Folder 2: 60)
  - Davidovich, Boris, 1953 (Folder 2: 61)
  - Davis, Malcolm W., 1941-1942 (Folder 2: 62)
  - Debyser, F., 1946-1947 (Folder 2: 63)
  - Degouys, L., 1944 (Folder 2: 64)
  - Delevsky, J., 1938-1939 (Folder 2: 65)
  - Del'vig, V. S., 1949 (Folder 2: 66)
  - Dembo, Roza, 1955 (Folder 2: 67)
  - Demidov, Igor, 1934-1939 (Folder 2: 68)
  - Denike, U. P., 1947, 1966 (Folder 2: 69)
  - Denikina, Ksenia, 1964-1966 (Folder 2: 70)
  - Deriuzhinskaia, Natalia, 1963 (Folder 2: 71)
  - Dexter, Byron, 1940 (Folder 2: 72)
  - Didier, J.P., 1942 (Folder 2: 73)
  - Dingol, S., 1948 (Folder 2: 74)
  - Dinkin, 1945 (Folder 2: 75)
  - Dodd, Mead & Company, Inc., 1942 (Folder 2: 76)
  - Dolgopolov, N., 1940-1958 (Folder 2: 77)
  - Domogatzky, Boris, 1957-1963 (Folder 2: 78)
  - Dordopolo, V., 1948 (Folder 2: 79)
  - Dressler, William, 1941 (Folder 2: 80)
  - Dubnov, Simon, 1938-1939 (Folder 2: 81)
  - Duell, Charles, 1965 (Folder 2: 82)
  - Duker, Abraham G., 1943 (Folder 2: 83)
  - Dvinov, Boris, 1949-1956 (Folder 2: 84)
  - Ecker, Allan B., 1958 (Folder 2: 85)
  - Eckhardt, C.C., 1945 (Folder 2: 86)
  - Edelman, Milton, 1945 (Folder 2: 87)
  - Eizer, A., 1962 (Folder 2: 88)
  - Elbaum, Charles, 1955-1963 (Folder 2: 89)
  - Elkind, B., 1944-1945 (Folder 2: 90)
  - Elliot, Ellen, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Ellis, Elizabeth, 1946-1951 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Emergency Committee on Aid of Displaced foreign scholars, 1943-1944 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Emoukuvari, V., 1957 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Epstein, Julius, 1955 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Erukhmanov, A., 1961-1962 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Estrina, Ida, undated (Folder 3: 7)
  - Evans, Roger, 1942 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Ezer, Alexander, 1962 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Fabrikant, Victor O., 1925 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Farrell, Robert, 1967 (Folder 3: 11)
  - Fastenberg, R., 1941 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Fayer, Mischa H., 1949 (Folder 3: 13)
  - Fedoroff, Andrew, 1951 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Fedorov, N., undated (Folder 3: 15)
  - Fedorov, Vasilii G., 1938 (Folder 3: 16)
  - Fedotoff White D., 1943-1948 (Folder 3: 17)
  - Fedotova, Elena, 1944 (Folder 3: 18)
  - Feinberg, Natan L., 1946-1968 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Fessenko, Andrew and Tatiana, 1950-1969
    - 1950-1955 (Folder 3: 20)
    - 1956-1960 (Folder 3: 21)
    - 1961-1969 (Folder 3: 22)
  - Fetler, Pavel, 1944-1945 (Folder 3: 23)
  - Fields, Harold, 1945 (Folder 3: 24)
  - Fisher, Edgar, 1941 (Folder 3: 25)
  - Fischer, Joseph, 1952 (Folder 3: 26)
  - Florinsky, Michael T., 1940-1961 (Folder 3: 27)
  - Fomicheff, M., 1946-1958 (Folder 3: 28)
  - Fondaminsky-Bunakov, Ilia, 1924-1947 (Folder 3: 29)
  - Foster, Liudmila, 1969 (Folder 3: 30)
  - Frank, Tatiana, 1959 (Folder 3: 31)
  - Francfort, C., 1939 (Folder 3: 32)
  - Frenkley, Alexander, 1950 (Folder 3: 33)
  - Fridman, S., 1927 (Folder 3: 34)
  - Frumkin, Jacob, 1946-1965 (Folder 3: 35)
  - Fry, Varian, 1943-1944 (Folder 3: 36)
  - Gabel, Leona, 1946 (Folder 3: 37)
  - Gaster, Theodore, H., 1941-1944 (Folder 3: 38)
  - Gavronsky, M. C., 1944-1949 (Folder 3: 39)
  - Gazdanov, G., 1928-1939 (Folder 3: 40)
  - Gelernt, G., 1957 (Folder 3: 41)
  - Gelfgot, Alexander, 1919 (Folder 3: 42)
  - Gelman, Anatolii, 1946 (Folder 3: 43)
  - George, George-Louis, 1946 (Folder 3: 44)
  - Gerb, Ludvig, undated (Folder 3: 45)
  - Gerby, Louis Alexis, 1958-1964 (Folder 3: 46)
  - Gercentshtein, Anna, 1935-1936 (Folder 3: 47)
  - Germanova, Maria N., 1938 (Folder 3: 48)
  - Gerschenkron, Alexander, 1964 (Folder 3: 49)
  - Gerstein, Linda, 1961 (Folder 3: 50)
  - Gessen, S., 1947 (Folder 3: 51)
  - Gherman, Jean, 1966 (Folder 3: 52)
  - Gidel, Gilbert, 1932-1937 (Folder 3: 53)
  - Ginger, Alexander, undated (Folder 3: 54)
  - Ginsburg, Maria, 1941-1967 (Folder 3: 55)
  - Glandaz, L., undated (Folder 3: 56)
  - Glatzer, Bernice, 1968 (Folder 3: 57)
  - Gliksman, Jerry, undated (Folder 3: 58)
  - Goding, Stowell, C., 1943 (Folder 3: 59)
  - Goldammer, S., 1953 (Folder 3: 60)
  - Goldenweiser, Alexis, 1939-1960 (Folder 3: 61)
  - Golenistcheff-Koutouzoff, Elie, 1939 (Folder 3: 62)
  - Golovine, Nikolai N., 1938 (Folder 3: 63)
  - Gonopol'sky, Michael, 1965 (Folder 3: 64)
  - Goodman, Richard, 1947 (Folder 3: 65)
  - Gorbachevich, D., 1958 (Folder 3: 66)
  - Gorde-Rappoport, Michel, 1950 (Folder 3: 67)
  - Gordon, Anne, 1866-1967 (Folder 3: 68)
  - Gordon, Boris, undated (Folder 3: 69)
  - Gorham, Arthur, 1965-1966 (Folder 3: 70)
  - Gottschalk, Max, 1941-1943 (Folder 3: 71)
  - Goul, Roman, 1944-1966
    - undated (Folder 3: 72)
    - 1944-1950 (Folder 3: 73)
    - 1951-1953 (Folder 3: 74)
    - 1955-1956 (Folder 3: 75)
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 3: 76)
    - 1959-1966 (Folder 3: 77)
  - Gourvitch, G., 1939-1945 (Folder 3: 78)
  - Guseff-Orenburgsky, S., 1941 (Folder 3: 79)
  - Grabianka, Sewerin, 1924-1958 (Folder 3: 80)
  - Gratziansky, E., 1939 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Graves, Mortimer, 1944-1945 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Grib, Nikolai S., 1938 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Griffith, Thomas, undated (Folder 4: 4)
  - Grinberg, Khaim, 1941-1942 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Grossman, Meir, 1943-1959 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Grossman, Vladimir, 1944 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Gruner, Fred, 1943 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Grynberg, Roman, 1958 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Gurian, Waldemar, 1945 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Gustavson, R.G., 1944 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Gzell, A.A., 1939-1947 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Haimson, Leopold H., 1966 (Folder 4: 13)
  - Hall, D., undated (Folder 4: 14)
  - Hall, Hanson, 1944 (Folder 4: 15)
  - Halperin, A., 1948 (Folder 4: 16)
  - Halpern, Ben, 1946 (Folder 4: 17)
  - Hazard, John N., 1940-1961 (Folder 4: 18)
  - Hearn, Therese, 1964 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Heiden, Konrad, 1939 (Folder 4: 20)
  - Heiskell, Andrew, 1967 (Folder 4: 21)
  - Held, Adolph, 1956-1969 (Folder 4: 22)
  - Helman, Anatolii, 1946-1953 (Folder 4: 23)
  - Hero, Alice, 1946 (Folder 4: 24)
  - Hessel, Stephane, 1946 (Folder 4: 25)
  - Hessen, Joseph V., 1938-1939 (Folder 4: 26)
  - Hmara, Gregorii, 1938 (Folder 4: 27)
  - Hodazky, J.I., undated (Folder 4: 28)
  - Hohoff, Tay, 1942 (Folder 4: 29)
  - Holowko, T., 1926 (Folder 4: 30)
  - Hook, Sydney, 1943 (Folder 4: 31)
  - Hopper, Franklin, 1942 (Folder 4: 32)
  - Howe, Dayton, 1952 (Folder 4: 33)
  - Huntington, Chapin W., 1945 (Folder 4: 34)
  - Hurtubise, Claude, 1943 (Folder 4: 35)
  - IArmolinsky, A., 1957 (Folder 4: 36)
  - Ignat'ev, A., 1958 (Folder 4: 37)
  - Ipat'ev, V., 1938 (Folder 4: 38)
  - Israel, I., 1945 (Folder 4: 39)
  - Ivanikov, M., 1938 (Folder 4: 40)
  - Ivanoff, N., 1938 (Folder 4: 41)
  - Ivanov, B., 1963-1964 (Folder 4: 42)
  - Ivask, J., 1956-1957 (Folder 4: 43)
  - Jacobi, Abraham, 1959 (Folder 4: 44)
  - Jacobs, Norman, 1961 (Folder 4: 45)
  - Jacoby, Gerhard, 1946 (Folder 4: 46)
  - Jamieson, Ed, 1968 (Folder 4: 47)
  - Jarkovsky, A.B., 1944-1969
    - undated (Folder 4: 48)
    - 1944 (Folder 4: 49)
    - 1945 (Folder 4: 50)
    - 1946-1949 (Folder 4: 51)
    - 1950-1952 (Folder 4: 52)
    - 1953-1957 (Folder 4: 53)
    - 1958-1959 (Folder 4: 54)
    - 1960-1962 (Folder 4: 55)
    - 1963-1965 (Folder 4: 56)
    - 1966-1969 (Folder 4: 57)
  - Jaryc, Augusta, undated, 1941 (Folder 4: 58)
  - Jasny, Simon, 1945-1964 (Folder 4: 59)
  - Jchirkov, Geoege, 1944 (Folder 4: 60)
  - Jessup, Phillip C., 1940-1943 (Folder 4: 61)
  - Jones, Roberta, undated (Folder 4: 62)
  - Jordan, M., 1951 (Folder 4: 63)
  - Jurgenson, Anaita, 1946-1956 (Folder 4: 64)
  - Kader, Boris M., 1947 (Folder 4: 65)
  - Kagan, A., 1946 (Folder 4: 66)
  - Kalashnikoff, Nicholas, 1943-1961 (Folder 4: 67)
  - Karbach, Oscar, 1947 (Folder 4: 68)
  - Karpovich, M., 1940-1959
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 4: 69)
    - 1942 (Folder 4: 70)
    - 1943 (Folder 4: 71)
    - 1944 (Folder 4: 72)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - 1946 (Folder 5: 2)
    - 1947 (Folder 5: 3)
    - 1948 (Folder 5: 4)
    - 1949 (Folder 5: 5)
    - 1950 (Folder 5: 6)
    - 1951 (Folder 5: 7)
    - 1952-1955 (Folder 5: 8)
    - 1956-1959 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Kazdan, S., undated (Folder 5: 10)
  - Keepen, Leo, 1951 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Kent, Inez, 1966 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Keogh, James, 1968 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Kerensky, Alexander F., 1942-1969
    - 1942-1943 (Folder 5: 14)
    - 1944 (Folder 5: 15)
    - 1945 (Folder 5: 16)
    - 1956 (Folder 5: 17)
    - 1957 (Folder 5: 18)
    - 1958 (Folder 5: 19)
    - 1959 (Folder 5: 20)
    - 1960 (Folder 5: 21)
    - 1961-1962 (Folder 5: 22)
    - 1965-1969 (Folder 5: 23)
  - Kerner, David, 1949 (Folder 5: 24)
  - Kerner, Robert J., 1955 (Folder 5: 25)
  - Kheraskoff, Ivan, 1942-1966
    - undated (Folder 5: 26)
    - 1942-1945 (Folder 5: 27)
    - 1946-1947 (Folder 5: 28)
    - 1948-1949 (Folder 5: 29)
    - 1950-1951 (Folder 5: 30)
    - 1952-1954 (Folder 5: 31)
    - 1955-1956 (Folder 5: 32)
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 5: 33)
    - 1960-1966 (Folder 5: 34)
  - Kiewiet, C.W., 1943-1944 (Folder 5: 35)
  - Kirshner, Lewis H., 1944-1958
    - undated (Folder 5: 36)
    - 1944-1958 (Folder 5: 37)
  - Kissman, 1942-1945
    - 1942-1944 (Folder 5: 38)
    - 1945 (Folder 5: 39)
  - Kliaver, M.I., 1953-1960 (Folder 5: 40)
    - 1953-1954 (Folder 5: 40)
    - 1957 (Folder 5: 41)
    - 1958 (Folder 5: 42)
    - 1959 (Folder 5: 43)
    - 1960 (Folder 5: 44)
  - Knorring, 1939 (Folder 5: 45)
  - Knout, David M., 1938 (Folder 5: 46)
  - Kobiakov, Michael V., 1955 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Kocharovsky, K., 1938 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Kochergin, N., 1955-1968 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Koiransky, A., 1952-1968
    - undated (Folder 6: 4-10)
    - 1952-1959 (Folder 6: 11)
    - 1960-1968 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Korson, M.G., 1957 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Koutyrina, J., 1956-1963 (Folder 6: 14)
  - Kovalenko, Giorgio, 1939-1950 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Kovankovski, P., 1950-1956 (Folder 6: 16)
  - Kovarsky,Ilia N., 1938-1964
    - undated (Folder 6: 17)
    - 1938-1939 (Folder 6: 18)
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 6: 19)
    - 1942-1943 (Folder 6: 20)
    - 1944-1946 (Folder 6: 21)
    - 1947-1948 (Folder 6: 22)
    - 1949 (Folder 6: 23)
    - 1950-1951 (Folder 6: 24)
    - 1952-1953 (Folder 6: 25)
    - 1954-1955 (Folder 6: 26)
    - 1956 (Folder 6: 27)
    - 1957 (Folder 6: 28)
    - 1958-1959 (Folder 6: 29)
    - 1960-1964 (Folder 6: 30)
  - Krestovskaia, Lidia, 1939 (Folder 6: 31)
  - Krolov, Nikolai, 1938 (Folder 6: 32)
  - Krout, John, 1945-1946 (Folder 6: 33)
  - Krupenskii, M., 1968 (Folder 6: 34)
  - Krylova, Irina, 1954 (Folder 6: 35)
  - Krymov, V., undated (Folder 6: 36)
  - Kulemimn, K., 1947-1948 (Folder 6: 37)
  - Kurganov, I.A., 1951.1957 (Folder 6: 38)
  - Kurgansky, M., 1933-1937 (Folder 6: 39)
  - Kuskova-Prokopovich, Ekaterina D., 1938-1959
    - undated (Folder 6: 40)
    - 1938 (Folder 6: 41)
    - 1940-1949 (Folder 6: 42)
    - 1950-1952 (Folder 6: 43)
    - 1955-1956 (Folder 6: 44)
    - 1957 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - 1958-1959 (Folder 7: 2)
  - Lachmund, Alice, 1961-1962 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Landay, Henry N., 1947 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Lasarson, M., 1938-1941 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Laskow, J., 1955 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Lasky, Melvin J., 1951 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Lasswell, Harold D., 1968 (Folder 7: 8)
  - Lebidinski, M., 1938 (Folder 7: 9)
  - Lednitskii, Vladislav, 1945-1948 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Lee, Algernon, 1942-1943 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Lehrman, Hal, 1967 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Leidesdorf, Samuel D., 1947 (Folder 7: 13)
  - Leites, Konstantin, 1944 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Leland, Waldo C., 1941 (Folder 7: 15)
  - Leoni, Edgar H., 1961-1962 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Lessen, Harold, undated (Folder 7: 17)
  - Levin, Arthur, 1965 (Folder 7: 18)
  - Levin, D., 1960 (Folder 7: 19)
  - Levin, V., 1953 (Folder 7: 20)
  - Levine, I.O., 1938-1939 (Folder 7: 21)
  - Levine, Isaac, 1941-1942 (Folder 7: 22)
  - Levinger, Wilhelm, 1946 (Folder 7: 23)
  - Levinson, Boris, 1944 (Folder 7: 24)
  - Levitas, S.M., 1943-1956 (Folder 7: 25)
  - Livne, Eliazar, 1954 (Folder 7: 26)
  - Levy-Bruhl, L., 1932-1934 (Folder 7: 27)
  - Lewin, Mendel, 1943-1947 (Folder 7: 28)
  - Lewitan, Joseph D., 1966-1968 (Folder 7: 29)
  - Liaskovskii, A., I., 1957 (Folder 7: 30)
  - Likhosherstov, A., 1948, 1953 (Folder 7: 31)
  - Lisowski, Eunice, 1940 (Folder 7: 32)
  - Literraturnyi Fond, 1944 (Folder 7: 33)
  - Lossky, N., 1938 (Folder 7: 34)
  - Lountz, Gregory, 1953-1967 (Folder 7: 35)
  - Lubar, George, H., 1948 (Folder 7: 36)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1946 (Folder 7: 37)
  - Luce, Henry R., 1961 (Folder 7: 38)
  - Lurie, A., 1936 (Folder 7: 39)
  - Lutz, P., 1958 (Folder 7: 40)
  - Luther, Michael M., 1955 (Folder 7: 41)
  - Lyons, Eugene, 1941-1957 (Folder 7: 42)
  - Mabeau, Michel, 1945-1950 (Folder 7: 43)
  - MacIver, R.M., 1945-1958 (Folder 7: 44)
  - Magerovsky, Lev F., 1955 (Folder 7: 45)
  - Makinsky, Alexander P., 1945 (Folder 7: 46)
  - Maklakov, Vasilii, 1945-1956 (Folder 7: 47)
  - Malamuth, Charles, 1943-1965 (Folder 7: 48)
  - Malone, Damas, 1942 (Folder 7: 49)
  - Malyshev, A.N., 1955 (Folder 7: 50)
  - Manoukhine, T., 1939-1959 (Folder 7: 51)
  - Mansvetoff, V., 1942 (Folder 7: 52)
  - Marcotte, Laverne, 1968 (Folder 7: 53)
  - Margolin, Jurii, 1951-1968 (Folder 7: 54)
  - Markoff, Vladimir, 1939-1959 (Folder 7: 55)
  - Markowitz, Harold and Violet, 1943-1944 (Folder 7: 56)
  - Marshak, A., 1945 (Folder 7: 57)
  - Martianoff, Nicholas N., 1961 (Folder 7: 58)
  - Martindell, Jackson, 1964 (Folder 7: 59)
  - Matthews, T.S., 1946 (Folder 7: 60)
  - Matussevisch, J., 1938-1939 (Folder 7: 61)
  - Maze, D., 1957 (Folder 7: 62)
  - Mazout, Anatole G., 1945 (Folder 7: 63)
  - McLaughlin, R., 1960 (Folder 7: 64)
  - McMillan, Dallas, 1953 (Folder 7: 65)
  - Meiersons-Simoni, L., 1939 (Folder 7: 66)
  - Meisner, D., 1939 (Folder 7: 67)
  - Melgunov, Sergei P., 1939-1955
    - 1939-1945 (Folder 7: 68)
    - 1946-1947 (Folder 7: 69)
    - 1948-1949 (Folder 7: 70)
    - 1950-1951 (Folder 7: 71)
    - 1952-1955 (Folder 7: 72)
  - Meltzer, Julian L., 1958 (Folder 7: 73)
  - Mett, M., 1951 (Folder 7: 74)
  - Micheles-Dean, Vera., 1940 (Folder 7: 75)
  - Milioukov, Pavel N., 1936-1941
    - undated (Folder 7: 76)
    - 1936-1938 (Folder 7: 77)
  - Milioukov, Pavel N., 1936-1941
    - 1939-1941 (Folder 7: 78)
  - Miller, Alphonse B., 1944 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Miller, Barton S., 1944 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Miller, Herbert, 1942-1944 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Miller, John, 1944 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Miner, Justus J., 1967 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Minkoff, Isaiah M., 1943 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Mirkine-Guetzeyitch, B., 1940-1946 (Folder 8: 7)
  - MIschenko, A., 1950 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Mochul'skii, K., 1938 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1943 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Mohrenschildt, Dimitri, Von, 1948-1962 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Moreli, A., 1950 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Morgulis, G., 1939, 1942 (Folder 8: 13)
  - Morot-Sir, Edouard, 1966 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Morsch, Lucile, 1966 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Mosely, Philip E., 1941-1959 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Mowshowitch, D., 1943 (Folder 8: 17)
  - Muhlstein, Anatole, 1942 (Folder 8: 18)
  - Munson, Halsey J., 3rd, 1948-1957 (Folder 8: 19)
  - Nabokoff, (Nabokov), Vladimir, 1938-1955
    - 1938-1939 (Folder 8: 20)
    - 1955 (Folder 8: 21)
  - Nagivine, Ivane, 1932-1938 (Folder 8: 22)
  - Navon, Anita, 1968 (Folder 8: 23)
  - Nedoshivina, lidia, 1940, 1949 (Folder 8: 24)
  - Nemirovsky, Irene, 1939 (Folder 8: 25)
  - Nesterova, Ol'ga, 1968 (Folder 8: 26)
  - Nesvad'ba, V., 1957 (Folder 8: 27)
  - Nicolaevsky, Boris I., 1939-1965
    - 1939-1945 (Folder 8: 28)
    - 1960-1965 (Folder 8: 29)
  - Nikolaev, Semen, 1961-1965 (Folder 8: 30)
    - 1961-1962 (Folder 8: 31)
    - 1963-1965 (Folder 8: 32)
  - Nikitin, V.P., 1938 (Folder 8: 33)
  - Nol'de, Boris E., 1947, 1967 (Folder 8: 34)